Ihechi Festus

Front End Developer

Frontend developer with around 3 years of experience building scalable, efficient, and maintainable applications from start to finish. I contribute collaboratively in teams and, because of my quick learning ability, I don't hesitate to experiment with new technologies when necessary. I excel in planning and execution, as well as dealing with challenges, and I'm eager to join an agile team that values growth and will challenge me to use my diverse set of skills to achieve the best work possible.

ihechifestus999@gmail.com	+2348132770015
O Jos, Plateau 930222, Nigeria	ihechifestus9.web.app
in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ihechi-festus/	y twitter.com/Festuslhechi
github.com/The-Professor99	

SKILLS

Angular	Re	act	Redux		Java:	Scrip	ot	нтмі	-	Python		ТуреЅсгір	t	CSS	SASS
Bootstra	р	Mater	rialUI	Ta	ilwin	dCSS	S	Jest	Су	press and	l Cı	ıcumber	We	bpack	Figma
Kanban	No	otion	Bash		Git React Testing Library				агу	Content Writing and Research					
Flask	Gc	ogle	Cloud	R	xJS	S	Sock	et.lO	Po	stgreSQl	L	Firebase			

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Frontend Developer

GotRight Technologies

- 07/2022 Present
- Primarily assigned the role of implementing the functionalities of the website in a 3-person remote development team that created the MVP for the company.
- Largely responsible for implementing the website's functionalities, these include account registration, login and recovery, music release, user, artist and label management, admin functionalities, payments, and other functionalities in between. These were done by consuming API from the backend server.
- By prioritizing functionalities over design, I was able to deliver expected features of the platform in a short period of time.
- You can access the platform, which deals with music distribution, at https://www.yivera.com.

Fullstack Developer

Syftset Technologies

05/2022 - Present

- A personal project that I started from scratch and have continued to develop till this point.
- Built everything from the front end to the backend and everything in between, including contents written.
- Built the frontend of the website **using React** and some part of the backend **using Flask**. User authentication, storage, push notifications and analytics were handled using Firebase.
- Used Socket.io and Flask-SocketIO to create real-time communication between clients and the server and to handle automatic reconnections. These socketIO connections were also used to broadcast events from the server to all connected clients whenever new prediction data were generated.
- Connected the front end to the backend and also took care of the website's hosting and deployment.

- I had to pick up a lot of skills on the job such as using websockets and flask(for the backend).
- Website link: https://syftset.com
- Project Guide: https://medium.com/@syftset_technologies/cryptocurrency-price-predictions-a-guide-to-using-syftsets-buy-and-sell-signals-e7e820b0cbe8

Career Break

Study Leave

02/2021 - 02/2022

- Took an intentional pause to focus on my final year coursework.
- During this period, I had the opportunity to explore the blockchain(cryptocurrency) industry and also familiarized myself with a few Google Cloud Platform tools, such as Cloud Functions, Cloud Storage and Cloud Scheduler.
- Graduated and eager to put my newfound skills and knowledge to work.

■ Freelance Frontend Developer

Unique Help Global Concept Limited

11/2020 – 03/2021 Achievements/Tasks

- I was in charge of the company's website, namely in terms of building the front end **using Angular**, as well as overseeing and managing its progress.
- Working independently with minimal supervision and in a fast-paced environment, my duties ranged from designing the website to writing content for it and also bringing the said designs to life through code.
- Built all users' and administrators' pages and their functionalities.
- Made use of tools such as Postman (for API testing) and Google Analytics(To monitor site engagements and visits)

Front End Web Developer (Student Intern)

Nhub Foundation

09/2019 – 02/2020

Tasks

- Worked with team members to build various web-powered initiatives.
- Actively wrote content for use on projects worked on and assisted with the front end development of these projects.
- Planned and Created Dataflow Diagrams as well as other charts such as Use Case and Entity Relationship Diagrams for the projects undertaken using Lucid Chart.
- Led some teams in pitching projects' goals and projections to stakeholders.
- Tutored some of my peers on HTML/CSS and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering(B.Eng)

University of Jos

08/2015 - 11/2021

Jos, Nigeria

Study Program

• Electrical and Electronics Engineering.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Built https://syftset.com (05/2022 - present)

- A cryptocurrency price predictions platform built using React for the front end and Flask for the backend.
- The platform has gone on to reach 100+ users.
- The platform also has a social app interface through which users can make posts on topics relating to cryptocurrencies, engage other users' posts, and connect with other users to receive updates on their posts.

Built ecommerce-practice-99.netlify.app/ (03/2022 - 04/2022)

• An Ecommerce practice website I built while learning React.

Built a Face Recognition-based Class Attendance Management Application. (09/2021 – 11/2021)

- Built the application from ground up to completion using Python's machine learning libraries, OpenCV's computer vision and PyQt6 for the GUI.
- The project can be accessed here (https://pypi.org/project/CAMSyFReT/)

Built a Solar Tracker (Mini Project) (06/2019 – 08/2019)

• A Mini School Project.

CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate of Completion (06/2019 - 08/2019)

Google IT Automation with Python Professional Certificate - (coursera.com)

Certificate of Completion (06/2019 - 08/2019)

Mobile First Responsive Web Design – (pluralsight.com)

Certificate of Completion (06/2019 – 08/2019)

Angular: Getting Started - (pluralsight.com)

Certificate of Completion (06/2019 – 08/2019)

JavaScript Best Practices – (pluralsight.com)

INTERESTS

earch Writing Machine Learning	Blockchain	Reading	Robotics	
--------------------------------	------------	---------	----------	--